You want a job in a bank, be it Axis Bank,
ICICI, Kotak, HDFC or any top
private sector bank.  A profile that
always has job openings on it.  It is very
high in demand.  Provides fast career growth
opportunities.  And the best
part is that there are great opportunities for freshers also.
Freshers
can also get jobs easily on this profile.  Yes
my dear friend, I am talking
about Relationship Manager profile.
Relationship Manager is a very good career
opportunity.  But many people do
not have any clarity about this profile,
what is this job profile?  What is your work going to be like
?  How much salary will you get?  How
can you apply for jobs?  And
most importantly how will you clear the interview?
You will get all these information in this video.
So watch this video
from start to end without skipping.  And
mostly in this video I will tell you
how much salary different private sector banks give to a fresher relationship manager.
So this video is going to be very
valuable.  So please
like the video, subscribe to the channel and
we will start this video.  As
we move forward in the video and go into full detail,
I want to remind you of one thing you probably already know.  If you
write something down, the chances of its completion
increase significantly.  So
if you want to work on the profile of a Relationship Manager, then
definitely write in the comment that I
want to become a Relationship Manager or I am ready for a bank job,
then the Universe will also help you
in getting this job profile easily.  So let's
start the video and know
what is Relationship Manager.  My dear
friend Relationship Manager which is
called RMB in banking.  Its job is to
provide services to existing customers
and provide information to new customers about banking
products and services such as loans,
insurance, credit cards and mutual
funds.   The
job of a relationship manager is to
maintain relationships with customers.
Resolving customer queries,
maintaining customer trust in the bank.
And while doing all this,
sell banking products and services,
cross sell them and increase banking business.  In
a way, we can say
that RM is the
front face of the bank and its round shape is
very simple.  Keeping customers happy
and increasing banking business.  Now let's
talk about daily work.  There are
two types of RMs in banks.  The
first is the retail relationship manager who
serves normal customers.
All the product services that I mentioned are
pitched, sold and cross-sold to the banking products and services customers.
Second are Wealth or
Priority RM.  They
serve customers who have
good deposits.  The criteria of each bank is
different.
In many banks, customers with a minimum deposit of Rs 10 lakh are
considered priority customers.
Talking about daily tasks,
relationship managers call customers daily.  Let's
discuss about the products.
Conduct meetings after field visits.
Follow up on KYC and documentation.
And most importantly, by doing all this, we
achieve the sales target.  I hope your
profile has also been cleared.
What work you have to do has also become clear.  Now let's
talk about the issue which is salary.
After all, how much salary will you get on this profile
?  My dear friend, on the Relationship Manager
profile, you not only
get a fixed salary but you also
get incentives and performance bonuses.
Now let me tell you
what is the salary structure in different banks.
If we talk about ICICI, then profiles ranging from Rs 3.5 lakh to Rs
5 lakh per annum are available, in HDFC, profiles ranging
from Rs 4 lakh to Rs 6 lakh per annum are available, in Axis,
profiles ranging from Rs 3 lakh to Rs 5 lakh per annum are available.
As I said earlier, performance
bonuses are also available.  So if you
perform well then you can
easily achieve salary packages ranging from minimum Rs 6 lakh to Rs 8 lakh in
these banks.  Now
the question in your mind would be
why the salary range is being mentioned?  The salary range
depends on the location where you are joining.
Salaries are higher in metro cities.  Salary is
a little less in rural areas.  Now an
obvious question must be coming to your mind that
how will you get a job on this profile?  If you
are a fresher then you do
not need to worry at all.  Whether you have done
BBA, BCom,
MBA or even BA,
you are eligible for this profile.
Talking about age, your age should be less than 27 years.
And if we
talk about the criteria of percentage marks, then if you have 50% and above in
10th, 12th and graduation then
you are eligible.  To apply,
you must have an ATS-friendly resume
and after that, you
can start your application process.  You
can apply in different ways.  The first
way is the career page of every bank.
Be it Axis, HDF or ICICI.
Each bank has its own dedicated career page.   Go there and
create your profile
and search for profiles like Relationship Manager or Business Development
Officer, Sales Officer etc.
You will
see a lot of job opportunities.
Apply for those opportunities using your
ATS-friendly resume.  Apart from this,
you can also find out jobs for Relationship Manager profile on Lindin and different job portals.
I recommend you to
create your profile on Founded because as of
today there are a lot of job
opportunities in the banking sector on Founded
and the competition on this job platform is
very less.  So your chances of selection will
increase significantly.  Just like you
sign up on any social media,
you can sign up in the same easy way.  The
link is given inside the description section.  Go sign up from there
and make sure to complete your profile 100%.  Only then
your chances of selection will
increase.  If you
want to work on any profile in the bank, then
you should definitely start improving two or three things.  First of all,
improve your communication skills.  Also,
you should provide knowledge of banking products and services.
Know the banking industry.
Because this will help you a lot in cracking the interview.
This is
how you can apply for a job.  Now let
us understand in a little more detail
how you will crack the interview.
To crack the interview, you need to know some
questions which are always asked,
repeatedly.  We have to prepare for them before going.
If you
give perfect answers to those questions then your chances of selection will
increase a lot.
What are these questions?  These questions are tell me something about
you.
How will you handle a customer getting angry with you
?  How will you meet your targets
?  Why do you want to work in the banking sector
?
Why do you want to work as a Relationship Manager profile
?  What are the products and services of banking
?  Many more similar
questions can be asked from you.
So prepare for their answers
and whenever you are answering,
answer with confidence.  Keep a smile on your face and
maintain eye contact with the interviewer.  Friends, if you
want to make your career in the banking sector, then
our course Main Bhi Banker
can help you a lot in this.
Now everyone will become a banker.  Banker.
Every step in this course has been explained in great detail.  It has been
explained in very simple language.  Not only have I
covered videos.  Along with this, you have been given
ready to do templates.
You just have to find your own information inside the resume.
You will get the complete format.
And also six e-books have been given with the
help of which you will be able to crack your job.  After
completing this course, many
people have already got jobs in the bank
and next is your turn.  So do
not miss this chance at all.  Actually the
price of this course is ₹2000.  But right
now this course is running at a special discount.  The
price of the course is only Rs 499
and if you join this course then
you get chat support.  If you have
any doubts or questions,
we help you here also in our
dedicated app.  Now the most important thing
that you have to listen to carefully is that
if you take this course and
after studying this course completely, you feel
that you did not get any value addition, you did not
learn anything, you did
not get any help, then you should contact me on my Instagram.
Your full amount will be refunded.
The condition is that you have to
buy the course.  You have to study the course completely
and even after that if you feel that you have
not been helped then you can connect with me
and you will be given a full refund.  This alone will give
you assurance about
how powerful this course is.  So the
link is given inside the description section.  Go and
purchase this course and I am pretty sure
you will get a job in a bank very easily.
Now I am going to tell you a very important
thing.  Banks
value their relationship managers a lot.  Why?  Because
relationship managers are the ones who
keep customers satisfied and
bring revenue to the bank.  Right?
Everyone respects the person who gives output
and wants to retain him.
So if you join the bank as a relationship
manager profile
and perform well,
your chances of growth are also quite good.
So many people comment and ask
how our growth will be in the future, so
I will tell you that also quickly.
You join as a relationship manager.
After that you become a Senior Relationship Manager.
After that you become a branch manager and the
next profile is cluster head.  And
as you continue to perform, the
better your performance, the faster your
growth will stop.  Even on the senior
profiles.  Talking about pressure,
this is definitely a customer facing role.   It
is a target driven role.  If you have to do sales then the
pressure remains within this profile.
I do
not decline this at all.  But if you learn to manage the pressure
,
maintain good relationships with customers, and
bring good business to the bank, then no
one can stop your growth.  So focus on customer
relationships and building your skills and
network.  You will be rewarded very nicely.
So I hope in this video you have got to
know every detail about the job of Relationship Manager.  If this
video has helped you in any way, then please
like the video.  Subscribe to the channel.  If you have
any questions or doubts in your mind,
please
tell us by commenting.  I will meet you
in the next video and I definitely tell you that
if you want to make your career in the banking sector then
our course Main Bhi
Banker can be a game changer for you.   The
link is given inside the description section.
Go and enroll right now.
Thank you for watching this video.  I'll see
you in the next one.